1. logInfo("Step 0: Resolve RequestObject from Object Repository")
5. request = findTestObject("Object Repository/API AI Demo/Users/GET Users")
9. assert request != null : "Request object not found: Object Repository/API AI Demo/Users/GET Users"
13. logInfo("Step 0.1: Ensure Content-Type=application/json header exists on the request object")
17. headers = (request.getHttpHeaderProperties()) ? request.getHttpHeaderProperties() : []
21. hasContentType = headers.any()
25. if (!(hasContentType))
1. request.setHttpHeaderProperties(headers + [new com.kms.katalon.core.testobject.TestObjectProperty(Content-Type, com.kms.katalon.core.testobject.ConditionType.EQUALS, application/json)])
5. logInfo("Added Content-Type: application/json header to request object at runtime")
29. logInfo("Step 1: Open endpoint http://localhost:3000/api/users (via GET request)")
33. logInfo("Step 2: Perform GET request to retrieve user details")
37. response = sendRequest(request)
41. logInfo("Step 3: Validate HTTP 200 response code")
45. verifyResponseStatusCode(response, 200)
49. logInfo("Step 4: Parse response body and extract usernames")
53. responseBody = response.getResponseBodyContent()
57. logInfo(Response body: $responseBody)
61. json = JsonSlurper().parseText(responseBody)
65. usersCollection = null
69. if (json instanceof java.util.Collection)
1. usersCollection = json
73. assert usersCollection != null : "Could not determine users collection from response JSON. Expected array or  or ."
77. usernames = usersCollection.collect()
81. logInfo("Usernames found:")
85. usernames.each()
89. logInfo("Step 5: Validate 'bankinguser123' is included")
93. assert usernames.contains("bankinguser123")
1. println(testCaseContext.getTestCaseId())
5. println(testCaseContext.getTestCaseStatus())